ebikeinsurance.co.uk 2016-05-03

# eBike - Privacy & Security

* #### Introduction

eBike (part of the Brightside Group) is committed to both respecting your privacy and providing a secure website so your personal information is protected. You can be assured any information you provide to us will be used strictly in accordance with the terms laid out in this statement.

Back to top
* #### Collecting Information

We will only look to request necessary information from you and will only use and disclose this information in the course of arranging and administering your insurance, and to inform you of other services which we feel may be appropriate to you. The type of information we will collect will include, for example, your name and postal address, date of birth, telephone number, email address, credit/debit card details and bank account details. The information we hold will be, to the best of our knowledge, accurate and up to date. Under the Data Protection Act you have the right to see the personal information that we hold about you in our records. All personal information is treated confidentially and is safely stored on our computer, with security systems preventing unauthorised access.

Back to top
* #### Confidentiality

We will endeavour to treat all your personal information as private and confidential. Other than under the terms of this privacy statement we will not disclose any of your information to anyone. We would like to bring your attention to our obligations to disclose information in the following exceptional cases permitted by law.

These are:

  * Where we are legally forced to.
  * Where there is a duty to the public to disclose information.
  * Where you have given permission to disclose information.
  * Where we have to protect our interest.

In the event that you have to make a claim then we will need to disclose information with any other parties involved in that particular claim. For example these parties may include the third party involved with the claim, the third party's insurer or the third party's solicitor. As highlighted in our Terms Of Business, your policy details will be added to the Motor Insurance Database (MID).

The MID is run by the Motor Insurers Information Centre (MIIC). MID data may be used by the DVLA and DVLNI for the purpose of Electronic Vehicle Licensing and by the Police for the purposes of establishing whether a driver's use of the vehicle is likely to be covered by a motor insurance policy and/or for preventing and detecting crime. If you are involved in an accident, the MID maybe used by Insurers, MIIC and the Motor Insurer's Bureau to identify relevant policy information. People pursuing a claim in respect of a road traffic accident may also obtain relevant information held on the MID. For more information visit [www.mib.org.uk](http://www.mib.org.uk/). eBike will also pass information to the Claims and Underwriting Exchange Register which is run by Insurance Database Services Limited (IDS Ltd), and the Motor Insurance Anti-Fraud and Theft register, run by the Association of British Insurers (ABI). The aim is to help us to check information provided and also prevent fraudulent claims. When dealing with your request for insurance these registers maybe searched. When you inform us of an incident, we will pass this information relating to it to the registers.

Back to top
* #### Information Security

How we protect your personal information from misuse and abuse is of great importance to us. We are constantly reviewing and enhancing our technical and physical security procedures to protect your personal data from unauthorised access. The eBike site also uses 128-bit secure socket layer (SSL) encryption technology to encrypt sensitive information such as your financial information. When you request a quote from us, we will process the data on a secure server.

Back to top
* #### How Your Information Will Be Used

Your information will be used for a number of purposes which include automatically processing your quotation, managing and administering your policy, claims handling and responding to complaints or policy enquiries. We will contact you to remind you your insurance is due for renewal.

From time to time, we'd like to get in touch with you by phone, email, SMS or post to tell you about the other products, services and special offers available from Brightside Group.

Your details are safe with us because we won't share your details with anyone else for marketing purposes. If you don't want to hear from us, simply opt out of receiving marketing communications by writing to our Marketing Department at:

Marketing Department  
Brightside Insurance Services Limited  
Brightside Park  
Severn Bridge  
Aust  
Bristol  
BS35 4BL

Or email them at [bike@brightsideinsurance.co.uk](mailto:bike@brightsideinsurance.co.uk).

Back to top
* #### Access To Your Information

You can write to us at any time to obtain details of the information we hold about you. Please write to:

Data Protection Officer  
Brightside Insurance Services Limited  
Brightside Park  
Severn Bridge  
Aust  
Bristol  
BS35 4BL  

Please quote your name, postal address and email address along with the details of your requirement. We will take reasonable steps to confirm your identity before providing you with details of any personal information we may hold about you. Therefore we would be grateful if you could provide two forms of identification such as a copy of a passport or driving licence and a copy of a utility bill to confirm address. In accordance with the Data Protection Act, 1998 we are entitled to charge £10 to cover the administration costs involved with this process. Please make cheques payable to “Brightside Insurance Services Limited”. Please see [www.ico.gov.uk](http://www.ico.gov.uk/) for our entry in the Information Commissioner's register of data controllers. Our registration number is Z5268008.

Back to top
* #### Cookies

Our web site use a number of different cookies. Here we explain the different type of cookies we use and why we use them.

##### What is a cookie?

Cookies are small text files placed on your computer by websites or sometimes by emails. They provide useful information to companies, which helps in all sorts of ways. For you, it means you can use our site more efficiently and save you time by not having to re-enter your details each time you visit. They also make sure you receive the most relevant information from us.

There are two main categories of cookies:

  * Persistent cookies - These cookies stay your computer until they are removed manually or automatically.
  * Session cookies - These cookies remain on your computer until you close your browser when they are automatically deleted.

##### Cookies we use and why we use them

##### Essential cookies

Essential cookies are technical cookies that are required for the operation of our sites. Without essential cookies our web site can't operate properly. Essential cookies include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas.

##### Performance cookies

Performance cookies allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors to our web site and to see how visitors move around them. This helps us to improve the way our web site works by enabling us to tailor our site to the way visitors use them. The information we collect from performance cookies is aggregated which means that we cannot identify you from it.

##### Your right to refuse cookies and what happens if you refuse them

You can refuse cookies by activating the relevant setting on your browser. However, if you do so you may not be able to access all or parts of our sites. If you carry on using our sites and do not change your browser settings we will assume you consent to us using cookies as described above.

Back to top
